{
    "id": "2630f09a1d6543f2814cce39fc05209d",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "We …………………………… to Greece next summer.",
            "description": "We use the present continuous tense to talk about pre-planned future events.",
            "answers": [
                "go",
                "will go",
                "are going"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I knew she ………………………….. before long.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, we use a past tense in the subordinate clause as well.",
            "answers": [
                "will arrive",
                "would arrive",
                "can arrive"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The Prime Minister ……………………………. London in December.",
            "description": "We use the simple present to talk about plans and schedules.",
            "answers": [
                "visits",
                "would visit",
                "is to visit"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Phone me when you ………………………….",
            "description": "In the subordinate clause we often use a present tense to refer to future.",
            "answers": [
                "arrive",
                "will arrive",
                "would arrive"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "‘I’m hungry.’ ‘I …………………………….. you something to eat.’",
            "description": "We use the simple future to tell people about a decision as we make it.",
            "answers": [
                "will get",
                "am getting",
                "would get"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………… I open the window?",
            "description": "Shall I is often used to ask for instructions. ",
            "answers": [
                "Shall",
                "Will",
                "Would"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………… you tonight.",
            "description": "We use the simple future to announce our decisions.",
            "answers": [
                "will phone",
                "would phone",
                "am phoning"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I will pay you back when I …………………………….. a job.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the future tense, we use a present tense in the subordinate clause to refer to future.",
            "answers": [
                "will get",
                "get",
                "would get"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "By next year, we …………………………………. here for twenty-five years.",
            "description": "We use the future perfect to say that something will have been achieved by a certain time in the future.",
            "answers": [
                "will be",
                "would be",
                "will have been"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………….. break his neck.",
            "description": "With the first person pronouns we use will in threats. ",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "shall",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I promise I ………………………………. do that again.",
            "description": "We use will in promises.",
            "answers": [
                "don't do",
                "won't do",
                "can't do"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "It is no use phoning them now – they ………………………………….. by now.",
            "description": "The future perfect can also be used to predict the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "will leave",
                "will have left",
                "would have left"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}